Cartel Land is a drama, documentary film directed by Matthew Heineman.
In the Mexican state of Michoacán, Dr.
Jose Mireles, a small-town physician known as "El Doctor," shepherds a citizen uprising against the
Knights Templar, the violent drug cartel that has wreaked havoc on the region for years.
Meanwhile, in Arizona's Altar Valley—a narrow, 52-mile-long desert corridor known as Cocaine Alley—Tim "Nailer" Foley, an American veteran, heads
a small paramilitary group called Arizona Border Recon, whose goal is to halt Mexico’s drug wars from seeping across our border.
Himself, played by Robert Hetrick.
Himself, played by José Manuel Mireles Valverde.
Self (as Tim 'Nailer' Foley), played by Tim Nailer Foley.
Self - Autodefensas Comandante, played by Paco Valenciano.
Self - drug cartel thug, played by Chaneque.
Self - drug cartel thug, played by Caballo.
Cartel Land is a 2015 American documentary film directed by Matthew Heineman about the
Mexican drug war, especially vigilante groups fighting Mexican drug cartels.
The film focuses on Tim "Nailer" Foley, the leader
of Arizona Border Recon, and Dr.
José Mireles, a Michoacán-based physician who leads the Autodefensas.
The film was nominated for the Academy Award for
Best Documentary Feature in 2016.
The film explores themes of mexico, arizona, cocaine, crack, murder.
The tone is dark and emotional.